# Juan Sebastian Caicedo Alfonso

Software developer | Electronic engineer

## **Projects**

#### MaiMovies - article video

Dec 2022 - Jan 2022

Mobile app to create and edit personal lists of audiovisual media. Developed with **React Native** and **Mobx** for **Android** and **IOS** 

#### Booking Experience - deployment video

Nov 2022 - Dec 2022

Website to deploy proof of concept ideas for clients of a booking website. Features in the first version: Creating new booking locations, creating, editing, and deleting bookings, changing theme according to machine preference supporting Android, IOS, and Windows. Build with **NextJs, ReactJs, and Redux** 

#### Port-ecommerce.shop - deployment

Oct 2022 - Nov 2022

Massive E-commerce website store. Full stack project, built with **Nextjs, React, Redux, Django, Graphql, docker, and Postgres**. It's fully deployed and implements features like the creation of accounts, authentication with JWT, image uploading and storing, profile editing, email password reset, and tag and search engine.

#### Order Management Application - video

Dec 2021 - Dec 2021

Full interface and restful API that handles the process of creating and processing orders for a retail company. Learned **React, Flask, css, bootstrap, sqlalchemy, and mysql**. It allows the user to log in, log out, create, display, and delete orders and clients.

#### Know your business - AltspaceVR MRE

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

Mixed reality extension for the AltspaceVR platform. It uses Nufi's APIs to allow users to do taxpayers and trademarks research in Mexico's archives in a 3D environment. Learned **typescript** and **altspace MRE SDK**.

#### Know your business - Web App

Sep 2021 - Oct 2021

Web application that uses Nufi's apis to retrieve information from any company. Learned **c#, and ASP.NET** as back-end and front-end frameworks. It uses an implementation of Model-View-Controller architecture (MVC).

## **Experience**

#### Software Developer - at Encora

Apr 2022 - Oct 2022

Migrating tool for intelligent process development in biopharmaceutical and biotech, recently acquired by the company. Learning and migrating technology from a heavy code load of more than 30 repositories. Technology stack: React, Python, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Gitlab CICD, AWS.

#### Software Developer - at Nufi

May 2021 - Apr 2022

Develop proof of concepts and new products for the company to work and sell, answering directly to the CEO. Developed a Whatsapp chatbot that retrieves info from public ids through OCR and delivers a full report of the people. Design and implementation of RESTFUL API both in the back-end and front-end. Develop apps that implement third-party APIs to obtain and store clients' data. Technology stack: React, React native, node.js, express, selenium, Stripe, Twilio, Python, Django.

#### Math/Coding Teacher - old teacher profile

May 2016 - May 2021

Autonomous teacher to students worldwide. Taught 12 students per week identifying their specific way of learning and creating dynamic and fun lessons while getting a student's rate of hiring again of 97%. Main topics: Javascript, Python, React, Java, linear algebra, differential calculus.

### **Details**

**(** 

jseb.dev



github.com/jsebdev



linkedin.com/in/jsebdev



jsebdev@gmail.com

### **Profile**

Software developer with a keen sense of detail and optimization. Thanks to my eagerness to learn and research I've developed different solutions for the Fintech Industry, including integration of automated messaging services, API design architecture, web scraping, and data manipulation.

I like to learn and use clean architectures, agile development methodologies, and front-end frameworks, especially React to build stunning user-oriented platforms.

## **Technical Skills**

- React
- React Native
- Nextjs
- Node.js
- Django
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Docker
- Graphql
- Rest
- MobX
- Redux
- CICD

## Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Conversational - Proficient

• French: Intermediate

## **Education**

### Front End Specialization

Nov 2021 - Jan 2022

Short specialization. Build several front-end projects in teams of 5 with a basis in **React, Webpack, and Babel**.

### Full stack software developer, Holberton School

Feb 2021 - Nov 2021

Holberton School is a peer-learning, project-guided, and self-learning-based full-stack software engineering school. During my time at Holberton, I was able to propose and lead 5 extra projects from the usual curriculum.

### Electronic Engineer, Universidad del Valle

2011 - 2016

Electronic engineering bachelor.

## **Courses & Certifications**

- Kotlin Course 2023
- Django Course: Testing, Static Files, Django Admin 2022
- Django Course 2022
- Professional Python Development Course 2022
- AWS Cloud Computing Compute, Storage and Databases 2022
- AWS Cloud Computing with EC2 2022
- AWS Cloud Computing roles and security with IAM 2022
- Introduction to AWS Cloud Computing 2022
- React Native Course 2022
- NextJs Course 2022
- Angular Course 2022
- React Course 2022
- Svelte Course 2022